Hello and welcome to this lecture.
And in this lecture we're going to talk something about modules that you so you might have heard the
concept about model of programming and more you know programming essentially means writing programs
into different chunks where each is actually called as a model.
Now if you take kids and the innocent off Mondial and programming model is actually a piece of code
which is written by other people or Also it might be written by you.
But the thing is that there are actually a bunch of Python modules available on the internet which are
written by different programmers and what to do is essentially is it is a set of code which is written
by them and you could go ahead and use that code in your program to do a particular task.
Also there are a bunch of modules which are built in Python which are developed by Python itself which
provide you with a bunch of functionality to perform different things.
So in this lecture you are going to learn how to actually use modules which are actually built in Python.
So we are going to take simple example of a random module.
The model would just call as random and we are going to use a function which is called as random and
to actually make a word or dice in Python.
So now let's go ahead how to use modules in our programs.
The very first thing which you need to do is that you actually need to import the module which you want
to use.
So as in this case if you want to use the random more do you type in import random.
This essentially does as that tells Python that we actually want to use the danda more deal in our code.
So it is going to be important and a model for us so that we could use those functions which are present
in the on the model.
So once you have this now let's sort of go ahead and write the code to actually create a what's your
advice.
So essentially what we are going to do here is that we are going to print out 5 to 6 random values by
using the different function which is present in the random model.
So I'm going to dive in for x as a for loop and then I'm going to dive in range and I'm going to specify
the range value to be 5 as you only want five things here.
And now let's go ahead and use the random function from the random more do you.
So whenever you want to access any function from Mordieu the first thing which you do is that you type
in the more do you will name which is random in this case so I'm going to type in random give a dot
operator and then as you could see there are a bunch of functions from the random module which you could
use.
But in this case if you want a function with just called Last around and which is going to return a
random integer value to us.
So this function actually acts stupid army does or does nothing but the range which is going to be let's
say 1 to 6.
And as this function returns some value as I said we need to store that particular value.
So let's say we create a new radio bill which is called Life as a result.
So I'm going to simply type in the result over here.
So I type result equals random dot random and I'm going to pass two values here.
So once I pass these two values to the function it is going to return as a result.
Now the only thing which we need to do is that we need to print out the result.
So I simply type out the end result and we are going to get 5 to 6 random values on this for loop right
here.
So if I see the code and if I executed as you could see we got some random values that is we got five
random values because we have specified the range as 5.
So you don't need to actually pay attention to the for loop or anything in this lecture.
But the only thing which you need to understand is that how to use modules.
So basically you use modules by importing them.
So you type import and the name of the model which you want to import.
Then once you have the more do you then in order to access a particular function in that more you type
the more you Leam give a dot operator and then type in the function name right after it.
So that basically allows you to use any function in any model which you have imported.
So that's it for this lecture and I hope you guys understood how to actually import it in more detail
and how to actually access any functions within that Marty.
So thank you very much for watching this lecture and I'll see you guys in the next lecture.
Thank you.